A Guide to the Papers of Sir Fitzroy Maclean 1827-1966
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Series II
  - Yugoslavia Material
    - Radio--Transcripts of BBC Radio Broadcast "Fitzroy Maclean's Memories of Tito" 1972-1974 (Box 23)
    - Television--Correspondence, Outlines, and Final Script for BBC Television Program "Life and Times of Marshal Tito" 1960-1965, 1973, 5 folders (Box 23)
    - Television--Correspondence and Scripts for BBC Television Tito Obituary 1967-1970 (Box 23)
    - Television--Comments on Belgrade TV (in Serbo-Croatian) 1968 Nov 27 (Box 23)
    - Television--Correspondence and Transcript of Interview with Tito for CBS News and Life Magazine 1968-1969, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Television--Outlines and Interviews for CBS News Program on Tito 1969 (Box 24)
    - Television--Correspondence 1970 (Box 24)
      re Film "General from Strachur"
    - Television--Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box 24)
      re BBC Television Tito Obituary
    - Television--Correspondence 1977-1978 (Box 24)
      re Tito Interview for CBS News
    - Television--Correspondence 1977, 1980 (Box 24)
      re Proposed BBC Programs
    - Television--Correspondence and Outlines 1981-1982 (Box 24)
      re Proposed Film on Tito
    - Television--Correspondence 1983-1984 (Box 24)
      re BBC Program on the S.O.E. (Special Operations Executive)
    - Television--Correspondence with Nordeutcher Rundfunk 1984 (Box 24)
    - Television--Correspondence 1984 (Box 24)
      re BBC Program on Evelyn Waugh
    - Television--Correspondence 1986-88, 1992-96, 2 folders (Box 24)
      re Miscellaneous Television and Film Projects
    - Television--Correspondence and Treatment for Proposed Television Series 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Television--Correspondence 1991-1992 (Box 24)
      re BBC Program "Ratlines"
    - Television--Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box 24)
      re VPRO Program
    - Television--Royalty Statements from BBC Television 1973-74, 1985-88 (Box 24)
    - Research Material 1963-1989, 7 folders (Box 25)
    - Research Material--Articles 1990-1995 (Box 25)
    - Research Material--Journal of the Yugoslav Communist Party, in Serbo-Croatian 1942 (Box 25)
    - Research Material--Maps n.d. (Box 25)
    - Research Material--Tito articles 1980, n.d. (Box 25)
    - Research Materials--United States Army Publication on German Anti-guerilla Operations in the Balkans 1954 (Box 25)
    - Research Material--World War II Offensive 1968 (Box 26)
    - Research Material--"Yugoslavia at the time of Changes by Admiral Mamula" [1989] (Box 26)
    - Research Material--"Yugoslavia and the Soviet Union" by Stephen Clissold 1975 (Box 26)
  - Russia & The Former Soviet Union Material
    - A Person from England--Drafts, most in notebooks ca. 1957-1958, 7 folders (Box 26)
    - A Person from England--Drafts ca. 1957-1958, 10 folders (Box 27)
    - A Person from England--Setting Copy, Prologue and Chapter 1-4 1958, 5 folders (Box 27)
    - A Person from England--Setting Copy, Chapter 5, etc. 1958, 4 folders (Box 28)
    - A Person from England--Correspondence with Jonathan Cape 1958-1959, 1967, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - A Person from England--Correspondence with Fans 1958-1959, 1967 (Box 28)
    - A Person from England--Correspondence 1990-1991 (Box 28)
      re New Edition
    - A Person from England--Correspondence 1959-1968 (Box 28)
      re Proposed Film
    - A Person from England--Correspondence with Publishers 1983-1986 (Box 28)
    - A Person from England--Correspondence and Notes 1950-1966, 2 folders (Box 28)
      re Research
    - A Person from England--Correspondence 1958-1962 (Box 28)
    - A Person from England--Book Reviews 1958-1962 (Box 28)
    - A Person from England--Film Treatment, First Draft, by John Mortimer [1960) (Box 28)
    - A Person from England--Research Material 1827-1861, 1957 (Box 28)
      Original Letters of Joseph Wolff and Correspondence with Ancient Light Bookshop
    - A Person from England--Research Material 1840-1842 (Box 28)
      Transcripts and Copies of Letters of Charles Stoddart and others from the Public Records Office
    - Back to Bokhara--Draft 1959 (Box 29)
    - Back to Bokhara--Correspondence 1958-1962 (Box 29)
    - Back to Bokhara--Correspondence 1959-1962 (Box 29)
      re American Edition and Other Projects
    - Back to Bokhara--Correspondence 1959-1962 (Box 29)
      re Copyright Renewal
    - Back to Bokhara--Advertising 1959 (Box 29)
    - Back to Bakhara--Contract with Jonathan Cape 1958 (Box 29)
    - Back to Bokhara--Fan Mail 1959-1964 (Box 29)
    - Back to Bakhara--Reviews 1959-1960 (Box 29)
    - "All the Russias" (published as To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus) Drafts ca. 1968-1970, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - "The Other Russias" (published as To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus) Draft ca. 1968-1971 (Box 29)
    - "The Other Russias and Then Mongolia" (published as To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus) Drafts ca. 1968-1972, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - "The Other Russias and Then Mongolia" (published as To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus) Draft ca. 1968-1972 (Box 30)
    - "The Other Russias and Then Mongolia" (published as To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus) Correspondence 1968-1972 (Box 30)
    - "The Other Russias and Then Mongolia" (published as To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus) Correspondence with Frank Herrmann 1970-1972 (Box 30)
    - "The Other Russias and Then Mongolia" (published as To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus) Notes and Research Material 1962-1971 (Box 30)
    - To the Back of Beyond--Manuscript Drafts in Notebook 1973, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - To the Back of Beyond--Drafts, Chapters 1-12 1973, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - To the Back of Beyond--Drafts, Chapters 13-15 1973 (Box 31)
    - To the Back of Beyond--Correspondence 1974-1984 (Box 31)
    - To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus Contract with Little Brown 1973 Oct 12 (Box 31)
    - To the Back of Beyond and To Caucasus Contract with Jonathan Cape 1974 Jan 7 (Box 31)
    - To the Back of Beyond Reviews 1974-1975 (Box 31)
    - To Caucasus--Manuscripts Drafts in Notebooks, Chapters 3-9 ca. 1970-1975, 2 folders (Box 31)
    - To Caucasus--Miscellaneous Typescript Drafts ca. 1970-1975, 5 folders (Box 31)
    - To Caucasus--Miscellaneous Typescript Drafts ca. 1970-1975, 12 folders (Box 32)
    - To Caucasus--Correspondence 1976-1977 (Box 32)
    - To Caucasus--Correspondence 1977-1981, 1990 (Box 33)
    - To Caucasus--Reviews 1976-1977 (Box 33)
    - Holy Russia--Manuscript Drafts in notebook, Chapters 1-9 ca. 1976, 6 folders (Box 33)
    - Holy Russia--Manuscript Drafts in notebook, Chapter 10-12 ca. 1976, 3 folders (Box 34)
    - Holy Russia--Typescript Drafts Chapters 1-12 1978, 4 folders (Box 34)
    - Holy Russia--Manuscript and Typescript Corrections ca. 1976-1978 (Box 35)
    - Holy Russia--Correspondence 1976-1986 (Box 35)
    - Holy Russia--Reviews and some Research articles from 1976-1977 1979-1982 (Box 35)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Drafts and Notes in notebooks 1978, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Drafts, Parts I-IV ca. 1978, 6 folders (Box 35)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Drafts, Parts I-II ca. 1985-1987, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Drafts in notebooks ca. 1985, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Drafts, Parts III-IV ca. 1985-1987, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Drafts, Parts I-IV 1987, 4 folders (Box 36)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Lists of Photographic Illustrations Sent to Collins 1986-1987 (Box 36)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Lists of Photographic Illustrations Sent to Collins 1986-1987 (Box 37)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union"Collated Picture Research" ca. 1986, 3 folders (Box 37)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Television Series Prospectus (James Higginson) 1977 (Box 37)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Television Series Prospectus (Richard Price) 1978 (Box 37)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Television Series Prospectus, Michael Gill and Jerome Gary 1981 Nov-1982, 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Television Series Prospectus (Visionaire) with Memorandum 1982 (Box 37)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Television Series Outlines 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Television Series Outlines 1981-83, 1985-86, 4 folders (Box 38)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Television Series Scripts, Parts 1-7 1987, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Correspondence 1974-1977, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Correspondence with Weidenfeld and Nicolson 1977-1980 (Box 39)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Correspondence 1980-1985, 9 folders (Box 39)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Correspondence 1986-1991, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Correspondence & Reviews 1988-1989 (Box 40)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Correspondence 1988-1989 (Box 40)
      re German edition
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Contract with George Weidenfeld and Nicolson 1987 Aug 20 (Box 40)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union Film--List of Expenses for Fitzroy Maclean 1985-1987 (Box 40)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union Film Research ca. 1985 (Box 40)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Filming Update Report 1987 Jun (Box 40)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Memoranda for Negotiations 1985 (Box 40)
    - Portrait of the Soviet Union--Schedules for Research Trip 1985 Dec-1986 Feb (Box 40)
    - All the Russias--Typescript Draft and List of Corrections 1988-1991 (Box 40)
    - All the Russias--Correspondence 1988-1996, 4 folders (Box 40)
    - All the Russias--Reviews 1992 (Box 40)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1949-1951 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--Stalin's Death 1953 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--"Eastern Re-Approaches" 1958 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--"A Caucasian Hollywood or Film Stars in Georgia" 1959 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--"Georgia Revisited" 1959 Sep (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1959-1961 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R.--"Trans-Siberian Journey Across the Heart of Russia" 1962 May 6 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1962-1963 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--"Russia's New Revolution" 1966 Feb 20 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--"Russia Looking Both Ways" 1967 Jan 29 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1967 Apr (Box 41)
      re the Sino Russian Border in Life
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--"Kosygin" 1968 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1970 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1973 (Box 41)
      re the Caucasus Region
    - U.S.S.R. Articles-- "Tbilisi The Georgian City That's Most Un-Russian" 1974-1975 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--"Forward" to Guide to Moscow 1974-1976 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles--"Imam Shamyl & the Kidnapping of the Georgian Princess" in Horizon 1975-1976 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1978-1984 (Box 41)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "British Week in Novosibirsk" and "Pskov: A Journey Into Russia's Past" 1979 (Box 42)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "Inside the Soviet Union" in Telegraph Sunday Magazineca. 1978-1980, Drafts, Galleys, and Printed; 4 folders (Box 42)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "Inside the Soviet Union" in Telegraph Sunday Magazine 1977-1980 (Box 42)
      Correspondence re
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1985-1987 (Box 42)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "Introduction" to Through Russia on a Mustang1988 (Box 42)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "Trial and Terror" in The Listener1988, 1994 (Box 42)
      re the Bukharin Trial in Moscow & Interview with his widow
    - U.S.S.R. Articles Anatoli Rybakov and Children of the Arbat1988 (Box 42)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "Forward" to Travels in 18th Century Russia1989 (Box 42)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "The Soviet Disunion" 1989 (Box 42)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1989-1991 (Box 42)
      re Mikhail Gorbachev
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1990-1991 (Box 43)
      re Georgia in The Sunday Times
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1990 (Box 43)
      re Azerbaijan
    - U.S.S.R. Articles 1990-1995, n.d. (Box 43)
      re Georgia, including notes and drafts
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "Foreward" to Alone Through the Forbidden Land1991 (Box 43)
    - U.S.S.R Articles 1991 & 1995 (Box 43)
      re Georgia in The Scotsman Magazine
    - U.S.S.R. Articles Interview with Edward Shevardnadze ca. 1995 Feb (Box 43)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles "Meeting the Russians" by Veronica Maclean n.d. (Box 43)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles n.d., Draft in notebook (Box 43)
    - U.S.S.R. Articles n.d., Draft in notebook (Box 43)
      re Caucasus
    - U.S.S.R. Book Reviews by Fitzroy Maclean 1949-1994, 5 folders (Box 43)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures--"The Answer to Russia" 1951-1952 (Box 43)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures 1958-1970, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures--"The Other Russias" 1968 Aug (Box 44)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures 1971-1978 (Box 44)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures--Writers Conference in Moscow 1975 Oct (Box 44)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures ca. 1982-1987, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures for Elizabeth Hill Russian Studies Appeal, with Correspondence 1988-1991 (Box 44)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures 1987-1992, 2 folders (Box 44)
      re Mikhail Gorbachov
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures 1989 (Box 44)
      re Mikhail Gorbachev in honor of Hugh Seton-Watson
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures--"All the Russias" 1992 (Box 44)
      given at Foyle's Lunch
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures 1992 (Box 44)
      re Georgia
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures n.d. (Box 44)
    - U.S.S.R. Lectures--"To Caucasus" n.d. (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Radio--Transcripts for BBC Radio "Siberia" 1952 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Radio--Talks for Scottish Schools with Correspondence 1958-1959 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Radio--BBC Radio "A New Look at Moscow" 1962-1963 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Radio--BBC Radio "Dr. Joseph Wolff", "Samarkand", and Others 1963-1965 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R Research Material in English and Russian 1939-40, 1944, 3 folders (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Scripts, etc. for BBC Television "The Road to Samarkand" 1958-1959 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Manuscript Draft Notebook and Scripts for BBC Television "The End of All the Earth" 1961 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Correspondence for BBC Television "The End of All the Earth", with Reviews 1961-1962, 1966 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Scripts and Reviews for BBC Television "The Other Russias" 1967 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Correspondence for BBC Television "The Other Russias" 1967-1973 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Correspondence for BBC Television "Carnival in the Caucasus" 1979-1983, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Correspondence for Central Independent Television "Spanish Civil War" 1984 (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Transcripts of Interviews with Anna Mikhailovna Larina, Dimitri Volkogonov, Anatoli Rybakov, Alec Nove, etc. for BBC Telelvision Series "Timewatch" featuring "Bukharin" 1988, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Outlines for BBC Television Series "Timewatch" 1988 (Box 46)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Correspondence for BBC Television Series "Timewatch" featuring "Bukharin" 1988-1989 (Box 46)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Miscellaneous Programs 1988-1992 (Box 46)
    - U.S.S.R. Television--Proposals and Correspondence for Television Programs 1990-1994 (Box 46)
  - Scotland Material
    - A Concise History of Scotland--Correspondence with Thames and Hudson, and Others 1965-1975, 4 folders (Box 46)
    - A Concise History of Scotland--Correspondence with Thames and Hudson 1992-1993 (Box 46)
      re a New Edition
    - A Concise History of Scotland--Correspondence 1974-1986 (Box 46)
      re an American Edition
    - A Concise History of Scotland--Correspondence 1984-1988 (Box 46)
      re a German Edition
    - A Concise History of Scotland--Reviews 1970 (Box 46)
    - A Concise History of Scotland--Royalty Statements 1974-1995 (Box 46)
    - The Isles of the Sea--Manuscript Drafts in notebooks ca. 1980-1984, 5 folders (Box 47)
    - The Isles of the Sea--Typescript Drafts ca. 1984, 3 folders (Box 47)
    - The Isles of the Sea--Setting Copy 1985, 4 folders (Box 47)
    - The Isles of the Sea--Galleys, with a letter 1985 (Box 48)
      August 1, 1996 from Edwin Moore to Veronica Maclean
    - The Isles of the Sea--Page Proofs 1985 (Box 48)
    - The Isles of the Sea--Correspondence 1983-1989, 2 folders (Box 48)
    - The Isles fo the Sea--Correspondence 1984-1990 (Box 48)
    - The Isles of the Sea--Correspondence 1989-1996 (Box 48)
      re reprint as West Highland Tales
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Manuscript Drafts in notebooks, Foreword and Part I ca. 1970-1987, 4 folders (Box 48)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Manuscript Draft in notebooks, Part II ca. 1970-1987, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Manuscript Draft in notebooks, Part III, Chapters 13-18 ca. 1970-1987, 3 folders (Box 49)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Manuscript Drafts in notebooks, Part III, Chapters 19-22 ca. 1970-1987 (Box 50)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts, I, II, & III ca. 1970's, 7 folders (Box 50)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts IV, Chapters 19-22 ca. 1970's, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts III & IV, Miscellaneous Chapters ca. 1970's, 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts I & II ca. 1980-1987, 8 folders (Box 51)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Draft, Parts III & IV ca. 1980-1987, 4 folders (Box 52)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts III & IV ca. 1980-1987, 5 folders (Box 52)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts I & II ca. 1980-1987, 4 folders (Box 52)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts III, IV, Index, and Miscellaneous Corrections ca. 1980-1987, 5 folders (Box 53)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts I & II, Chapters 1-9 ca. 1987, 6 folders (Box 53)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Typescript Drafts, Parts II, III, & IV, Chapters 10-22 and Bibliography ca. 1987, 7 folders (Box 54)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Correspondence with George Weidenfeld and Nicolson, and Others 1969-1991, 3 folders (Box 54)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Correspondence with Fans and Others 1988-1995, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Bonnie Prince Charlie--Reviews and Related Articles 1988 (Box 54)
    - "Land of Scotland" Proposed Book--Correspondence 1985-1988 (Box 54)
    - Highlanders--Manuscript Drafts in notebooks ca. 1980's, 4 folders (Box 55)
    - Highlanders--Typescript Drafts ca. 1980's, 6 folders (Box 55)
    - Highlanders--Typescript Drafts ca. 1980's, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Highlanders--Typescript Drafts 1994 Jan, 4 folders (Box 56)
    - Highlanders--Typescript Drafts 1994 Sep, 4 folders (Box 56)
    - Highlanders--Typescript Drafts, Glossary 1994 Sep (Box 57)
    - Highlanders--Typescript Drafts, Corrections 1994 (Box 57)
    - Highlanders--Correspondence with Thames and Hudson, Weidenfeld and Nicolson, and Others 1980, 1989-90 (Box 57)
    - Highlanders--Correspondence with Everyman's Library and Others 1994-1995 (Box 57)
    - Highlanders--Correspondence 1995 (Box 57)
      re Publicity & Book Reviews
    - Highlanders--Research Material 1970-1994 (Box 57)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Correspondence 1981-1993, 6 folders (Box 57)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Correspondence and Research Material 1992-1994 (Box 57)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Correspondence 1994-1996, 3 folders (Box 58)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Correspondence 1995-1996 (Box 58)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Clan Histories ca. 1980's (Box 58)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Notes ca. 1980-1981 (Box 58)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Outlines 1981, 1985, 1988, 4 folders (Box 58)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Treatment 1990 May 23 (Box 58)
    - Highlanders Television (Series) Treatment 1993 Apr & Sep, 2 folders (Box 58)
    - Scotland Articles 1957 (Box 59)
    - Scotland Articles "Scottish Approaches" in The Scotsman1959 (Box 59)
    - Scotland Articles 1960-1961 (Box 59)
    - Scotland Articles "The Macleans of Strachur" and "I Live in Argyllshire" 1962 (Box 59)
    - Scotland Articles 1975-1996, 6 folders (Box 59)
    - Scotland Articles "Arran, A Personal View" n.d. (Box 59)
    - Scotland Book Reviews by Fitzroy Maclean 1961-1994, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Scotland Lectures & Speeches 1962-1976 (Box 60)
    - Scotland Lectures & Speeches--Saint Andrews Society Banquets 1962-1964, 1978 (Box 60)
    - Scotland Lectures & Speeches--Miscellaneous Material 1975, n.d. (Box 60)
    - Scotland Lectures & Speeches 1978-1993 (Box 60)
    - Scotland Lectures & Speeches--Celtic Connections Festival 1994 (Box 60)
    - Scotland Radio--Correspondence 1960-1962 (Box 60)
      re "Scotland in Parliament"
    - Scotland Television--Miscellaneous Programs 1960-1962 (Box 60)
    - Scotland Television--"Scotland in Parliament" 1963-1964 (Box 60)
    - Scotland Miscellaneous Radio and Television Programs--Correspondence 1986-1991 (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous Literary Material
    - Take Nine Spies Manuscript Notebooks 1976-1978, 3 folders (Box 60)
    - Take Nine Spies Manuscript Notebooks 1976-1978, 6 folders (Box 61)
    - Take Nine Spies Manuscript and Typescript Drafts, Foreword, Epilouge, and Chapters 1-7 1976-1978, 11 folders (Box 62)
    - Take Nine Spies Manuscript and Typescript Drafts, Chapters 8-9 1976-1978, 3 folders (Box 63)
    - Take Nine Spies Contracts 1976-1978 (Box 63)
    - Take Nine Spies Contract--Books on Tape 1990 (Box 63)
    - Take Nine Spies Correspondence 1976-1986, 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Take Nine Spies Correspondence & Related Material n.d. (Box 63)
    - Take Nine Spies Correspondence--Greville Wynne 1977-1979 (Box 63)
    - Take Nine Spies Reviews 1977 Dec-1979 Oct (Box 63)
    - Articles 1946 (Box 64)
      re Japan
    - Articles 1946-1949 (Box 64)
      re Asia
    - Articles 1946-1950 (Box 64)
      re Korea
    - Article on Refugees for U.N.A. Year Book ca. 1947-1948 (Box 64)
    - Article on Eire and the Commonwealth 1948 (Box 64)
    - Articles 1949 (Box 64)
      re Italy
    - Articles 1949, 1958 (Box 64)
      re the Middle East
    - Articles 1951-1961 (Box 64)
      re Persia
    - Articles 1951, 1958 (Box 64)
      re Defense of Great Britain
    - Articles 1953 (Box 64)
      re Greece
    - Articles 1953-1957 (Box 64)
      re Libya during World War II
    - Articles 1953-1957 (Box 64)
      re Turkey
    - Article on Maclean's Military Training: "Feet on the Gravel" 1954 (Box 64)
    - Article on Hans ("Johnnie") von Herwarth: "A Drink Postponed" 1957 (Box 64)
    - Article: "Let's Have Selective Conscription" 1961 (Box 64)
    - Article: "Your Favorite Stories" 1961 (Box 64)
    - Articles 1963 Nov (Box 64)
      re China "Inside Red China"
    - Interview [1963] (Box 64)
      re China Trip
    - Articles 1963 (Box 64)
      re China "Peking Revisited," "Don't Let China Stew in Her Own Juice," and "Eyewitnesses in China"
    - Articles 1963-1964 (Box 64)
      re Mongolia
    - Articles & Tribute 1964-1975 (Box 64)
      re Sir Winston Churchill
    - Articles 1966-1970 (Box 64)
      Mongolia
    - Article on Turkey 1966 (Box 65)
    - Articles 1967-1968 (Box 65)
      re the Black Sea, including one by Veronica Maclean
    - Articles 1969-1970 (Box 65)
      re Defense of Europe: "Nuclear Deterrence and Conventional Forces," with Correspondence
    - Articles: "Wine Days" and "The Water of Life" 1982-1983 (Box 65)
    - Articles 1988-1989 (Box 65)
      re China--Trip to Kashgar in Chinese Turkestan, including Correspondence
    - Article: "Very Special Train" 1990 (Box 65)
    - Articles 1990-1991 (Box 65)
      re Nepal and Bhutan
    - Article: Gulf War 1991 Jan 10 (Box 65)
    - Articles 1991-1992 (Box 65)
      re Germany
    - Article 1992 (Box 65)
      re David Stirling for Dictionary of National Biography and Correspondence